Utw
Presents
Will one last miracle come to pass?
あと一度だけ奇跡は起こるだろう
Ato ichido dake kiseki wa okoru darou
A gentle voice paints a twisted future
優しい声で描く歪んだ未来
Yasashii koe de egaku yuganda mirai
For the sake of a world where nobody will cry
もう誰も泣かない世界の為に
Mou dare mo nakanai sekai no tame ni
Before reaching the crimson-stained sky
紅く汚された空の何処にも
Akaku kegasareta sora no doko ni mo
My cries and prayers fade and disappear
届かず消える叫びと祈り
Todokazu kieru sakebi to inori
I can go on, abandoning all consolation
慰めは捨てて行ける
Nagusame wa sutete yukeru
The beautiful moonlight shines towards the beginning and vanishes
綺麗な月の光が始まりへと沈み行く
Kirei na tsuki no hikari ga hajimari e to shizumiyuku
Into the distance
その彼方へ
Sono kanata e
I'll continue to reach out as my eyes are gradually closed
閉ざされてく瞳でまだ遠くへ手を伸ばす
Tozasareteku hitomi de mada tooku e te wo nobasu
I believe in your sorrow
君の嘆きを 信じて
Kimi no nageki wo shinjite
Killed?!
殺された
Impossible...
まさか そんな
Why would they kill the priest?
なぜ神父までもか
あってはならない
We can't allow this...
あってはならないことだ
We can't allow this!
It must be difficult for you to lose the priest like this.
こんな形で神父を亡くすとは君も嘸かし無念だろう
Yes.
Father Risei was like a second father to me.
璃生神父は私にとって もう一人の父というべきお方だった
It's been one unexpected thing after another.
ここまで予期せぬことばかり起こるとは
It might prove necessary to formulate some sort of plan right away.
至急　何か策を講じる必要があるかもしれない
なぜ時臣に言わなかった
Why didn't you tell Tokiomi?
何のことだ
What do you mean?
I pity your father.
哀れな父親だ
息子を聖人と信じて疑わずに逝ったのだからな
He died, believing his son to be a holy man.
No...
いいや むしろそれが救いか
Might that have been his salvation?
Does your father's death inspire no feeling within you?
父親の死に何の感情も抱かぬのか
殺されたのだぞ
He was killed, you know.
Shouldn't you at least look a little sad?
少しは悲しそうな顔くらい浮かべたらどうだ
Yes, it bothers me to no end.
ああ 悔しくてならない
悔しいか
Does it really?
Is it because you didn't get to kill him yourself?
それは自分の手で殺められなかったからか
Saber...
セイバー
アイスフィール 具合はどうですか
Irisviel, how are you feeling?
どうやら心配させてしまったみたいね
Looks like I made you worry.
I'm sorry.
ごめんなさい
It's fine.
いえ 本当に大丈夫であれば
As long as you really are all right,
I could ask for nothing more.
それに越したことはないのですが
But...
しかし
It's okay.
大丈夫 この気配は舞弥さんだわ
This presence is Maiya-san.
From Tohsaka?
遠坂から
Yes.
はい 遠坂時臣からの共闘の申し入れです
Tohsaka Tokiomi requests an alliance.
An alliance? Now?
同盟ですか 今になって
残るライダーとバーサーカーの対処に
Tohsaka must be uneasy at the thought of dealing with Rider and Berserker.
遠坂は不安を持っているんでしょうね
そこで一番与しやすいと見えた私達に誘いをかけてきた
We appear to be the team most inclined to form an alliance, so he invited us to meet.
In other words, he thinks us to be
the weakest compared to the others.
要するに他の二組に比べれば舐められてるってこと
Tohsaka said he wishes to meet tonight, at the Fuyuki City church.
遠坂は今夜冬木教会で会見の場を設けたいと言ってきました
遠坂時臣は今回の聖杯戦争において
Tohsaka Tokiomi has been making elaborate preparations for this Grail War from the very early stages.
かなり初期の段階から周到な準備を進めています
It's also likely that he's controlling Assassin's Master, Kotomine Kirei, from the shadows.
それに遠坂はアサシンのマスター
言峰綺礼を裏で操っていたと思われる節がある
If Tohsaka does exert some influence over
Kotomine Kirei, then we cannot ignore his offer.
遠坂が言峰綺礼に対して影響力を及ぼしうるなら
彼の誘いは我々にとっても無視できないかと
そうね
Indeed.
Kotomine Kirei...
言峰綺礼
Remember his name, Saber.
覚えておいて セイバー
If there is anyone who can defeat Kiritsugu and win the Holy Grail War,
今回の聖杯戦争で もし切嗣を負かして聖杯を獲る者がいるとしたら
it is Kotomine Kirei.
それが言峰綺礼という男よ
この話 受けましょう
We'll accept his invitation.
お父様
Father?
Father!
凛 お父様からお話があるそうよ
Rin, your father would like to speak with you.
Rin.
凛 成人するまでは協会に貸しを作っておけ
As you grow up, keep the Association in your debt.
それ以降の判断はお前に任せる
Beyond that, I'll leave the rest to your judgment.
You'll be fine on your own.
お前なら独りでもやっていけるだろう
One day, the Holy Grail will appear.
何れ聖杯は現れる
It is the responsibility of the Tohsaka family to obtain it.
あれを手に入れるのは遠坂家の義務であり
Above all...
何より 魔術師であろうとするなら避けては通れない道だ
If you wish to be a Mage, that is the path you must follow.
凛 これを
Rin, take this.
それでは行くが
Well, I'll be going now.
You know what to do from now on, right?
後の事は分かっているな
はい
Yes.
Goodbye, Father.
行ってらっしゃい お父様
不肖この遠坂時臣の招待に応じていただき
First, please allow me to thank you for coming at my behest.
まずは感謝の言葉もない
Let me introduce you.
紹介しよう 言峰綺礼
This is Kotomine Kirei, my student.
私の直弟子であり
一時は互いに聖杯を狙って競い合った相手であったが
While we were once competitors for
the Grail, all of that is now in the past.
今となっては過ぎた話だ
彼はサーヴァントを失い 既にマスター権も手放して久しい
He has lost his Servant and yielded his rights as a Master.
The Grail War is now heading toward its conclusion.
此度の聖杯戦争もいよいよ大詰めの局面となってきた
残っているのは 案の定「始まりの御三家」のマスターたちと
The remaining teams are, as anticipated, the Masters of the Founding Three Families, along with one outsider.
飛び入りの外様が一人
Now, how would you appraise the current situation?
さて この戦局をどうお考えか
別段何とも
Nothing I need to worry about.
Since we control Saber, the strongest Servant,
we don't need to wait for an opportune time to strike.
我らは最強のセイバーを統べるが故に
姑息に機を窺う必要もなく
We will simply keep winning each battle.
ただ当たり前に勝ち進むまでのこと
なるほど　当方の見解では残念ながら
I see.
In my opinion, it is unfortunate that the Matous erred in their strategy.
今回の間桐は戦略を誤った
脆弱なマスターに負荷のかかるサーヴァントを押し付け
They have imposed a draining Servant upon a weak Master, hastening his own destruction.
みすみす自滅を早めている有様だ
恐らく勝ち上がってくるのはライダーだろう
Rider is likely to emerge victorious.
The Grail must not be allowed to fall into outside hands.
外様の手に聖杯が渡ることは万に一つも許せない
The two of us should be able to agree on that much.
そこのところは お互い合意できるはずだ
同盟など笑止千万
Any alliance is out of the question.
ただし 敵の対処に順列をつけてほしいというのなら
However, if you wish to discuss the order in which we deal with our enemies,
そちらの誠意次第では一考してもいいでしょう
we may be able to come to some agreement.
つまり
Elaborate.
We can settle things with the Tohsaka camp after we defeat the other Masters.
遠坂を敵対者として見なすのは 他のマスターを倒した後
そういう約定なら応じる用意もあります
That's a proposal our side can agree to.
条件付の休戦協定 か
So a temporary, conditional ceasefire?
落としところとしては妥当だな
A fair compromise.
こちらの要求は二つ
We have two conditions.
まず第一に ライダーとそのマスターについて
First, you will share any information you have concerning Rider and his Master.
そちらが掴んでいる情報を全て開示すること
良いだろう
Very well.
Second, you will remove Kotomine Kirei from the Grail War.
第二の要求は
言峰綺礼を聖杯戦争から排除すること
綺礼
Remove Kirei?
I won't ask you to kill him.
何も殺せとまで言わないわ
それでも　この戦いが終わるまでの間
But until this war is over, I insist that he leave Fuyuki-no, Japan entirely.
この冬木から　いえ　日本から退去してもらいます
Before tomorrow morning.
さっそく明朝にでも
Could you explain why you'd want that?
理由を説明してもらえるかね
There is plenty of bad blood between
the Einzbern camp and the Executor.
そこの代行者は 我々アインツベルンと少なからず遺恨があります
If the Tohsaka camp continues to accept him,
遠坂の陣営が彼を擁護するのであれば
we will find ourselves unable to
trust you under any circumstances.
我々は金輪際 そちらを信用することはできない
What's the meaning of this?
どういう事かね
綺礼
Kirei.
どう 切嗣からの贈り物は
Well?
How do you like Kiritsugu's present?
It's closer to a horse than a car.
車よりも この騎馬に似た乗り物の方が私には性に合っているようです
It seems to suit me better.
I shall ride ahead and ensure that the route is safe.
では 私が先行して 帰路の安全を確認してきます
Let us go as well.
私達も行きましょう
M-Madam?
マダム どうしました
What's wrong?
Go ahead, Maiya-san.
行って 舞弥さん
But...
しかし
Tohsaka will realize something is amiss.
遠坂に不審がられるわ
異常ではないのよ これは
This isn't unexpected...
It was inevitable.
予め決まってたこと
In fact, it's a miracle that I've been able to function as a human for this long.
むしろ 今まで人として機能できたことが
私にとっては奇跡みたいな幸運だったの
Does Kiritsugu know about this?
切嗣も承知の上なのですか
Keep this from Saber.
セイバーには　内緒よ
She has a crucial battle ahead of her.
彼女は大事な戦いを控える身
余計な心配は　させたくない
I don't want her to worry about me.
だけど舞弥さん　貴方には話して置きたいわ
But Maiya-san, there's something I want you to know.
私は聖杯戦争のために設計されたホムンクルス
I am a homunculus created for the Grail War.
それはあなたも知っているわね
You know that, right?
Yes.
はい
Old Acht gave the vessel an instinct for self-preservation,
アハトのお爺様は「器」そのものに生存本能を与え
あらゆる危険を自己回避して聖杯の完成を成し遂げるために
so that it would avoid all danger and
safeguard the Grail to its completion.
He disguised the vessel under the veil of "Irisviel".
「器」に「アイリスフィール」という擬装を施したのよ
That's what I am.
それが 私
そんな では 貴女は
But that's...
Does that mean...?
Very soon, I will go back to being what I was.
これから先 私はもとの「モノ」に還っていくわ
次はきっと こうしてあなたと話をすることもできなくなるでしょう
Next time, I won't even be able to talk to you like this.
That's why Kiritsugu left Saber's scabbard with me.
だからこそ切嗣は 私にセイバーの鞘を預けたの
Avalon...
「全て遠き理想郷」 その効果は知ってる
Are you familiar with what it does?
老衰の停滞と無制限の治癒能力
It halts aging and has infinite healing power.
That's what I've been told.
そう聞いています
Its effects are what keeps the shell that is me from collapsing.
その効果が 私という「殻」の崩壊を押し留めてくれているの
もっとも セイバーとの距離が離れてしまうと
Of course, it can't work as well when Saber isn't nearby.
途端にボロが出るんだけど
Why are you telling me all this?
何故 私には教えたのですか
Hisau Maiya.
久宇舞弥 あなたなら決して私を憐れんだりしない
You would never pity me.
You'd acknowledge me.
きっと私を認めてくれる
そう思ったから
That's why.
マダム 私は貴女という女をもっと遠い存在だと思っていました
Madam, I...
I have always thought of you as a more distant figure.
That's not true.
そんなこと ない
分かってくれた
Do you understand?
Yes.
はい
Even at the cost of my own life...
私がこの生命に代えてでも
アイリスフィール 最後まで貴女をお守りいたします
Irisviel, I will protect you to the very end.
So...
だからどうか  衛宮切嗣のために死んでください
Please die for Emiya Kiritsugu.
あの人の理想を叶えるために
So his dream can become a reality.
ありがとう
Thank you.
アインツベルンとの経緯 やはり私には一言欲しかった
I would've preferred to have known
of your dealings with the Einzberns.
I'm afraid I have no choice.
残念ながら 致し方あるまい
この戦いから身を引いてくれ
You'll withdraw from the Grail War, Kirei.
綺礼
Emiya Kiritsugu...
衛宮切嗣 貴様は何者だ
Who are you?
それも分からぬまま 私はここを去るのか
Will I leave this place without ever finding out?
You're still pondering about it?
この期に及んで まだ思案か
How slow could you possibly be, Kirei?
鈍重にも程があるぞ 綺礼
今なお聖杯はお前を招いている
The Grail beckons you still.
そしてお前自身もまた なお戦い続けることを望んでいる
And you, yourself, still long to fight.
物心ついて以来 私はただ一つの探索に生きてきた
For as long as I can remember, I've lived my life searching for just one thing.
ただひたすらに時を費やし 痛みに耐え
I've spent all my time on it and endured
much pain, but all of it has come to naught.
その全てが徒労に終わった
And yet, I feel that I am closer to
the answer now than ever before.
なのに今 私はかつてないほどに問い質してきた答えを間近に感じている
Why do you still hesitate after all that self-examination?
そこまで自省しておきながら いったい何をまだ迷う
予感がある
I have a feeling...
全ての答えを知った時 私は破滅することになるのだと
...that I will destroy myself when I've learned all the answers.
分かった ご苦労
I see. Thank you.
何かよほど心が浮き立つような報せでも受けたのか
Did you just learn of some exciting new information?
アインツベルンの連中が隠れ潜んでいる拠点の調べがついた
I've discovered the location of the Einzbern hideout.
なんだ綺礼 お前というヤツは
You're incredible, Kirei!
You honestly amaze me!
もとより続ける覚悟なのではないか
You were going to continue this whole time.
I did hesitate.
迷いはしたさ
止める手もあった
I was prepared to stop.
だが結局のところ
But in the end, you're absolutely right, King of Heroes.
英雄王 お前の言うとおり
私という人間は ただ問い続けることの他に処方を知らない
I know of no other remedy than to continue my inquiry.
それは
What is that?
父からの贈り物だ
A gift from my father.
Jn424.
Jn424
ヨハネ福音書
The Gospel of John.
神は御霊なり
God is Spirit,
and those who worship Him must worship in spirit and truth.
故に神を崇める者は 魂と真理をもって拝むべし
しかしな 綺礼
However, Kirei...
A very serious problem remains.
さっそくだが 由々しき問題があるぞ
お前が自らの意志で聖杯戦争に参ずるならば
Should you participate in the Grail War of your
own will, Tohsaka Tokiomi becomes your enemy.
いよいよ遠坂時臣は敵であろうが
つまり今お前は何の備えもないままに
In other words, you're in the same room as an
enemy Servant with nothing to defend yourself with.
敵対するサーヴァントと同室しているのだ
Quite a dire situation you're in, aren't you?
これは大層な窮地ではないか
No.
そうでもない
命乞いの算段ぐらいはついている
I've thought of a way to beg for my life.
Oh?
ほう
ギルガメッシュ まだお前が知らぬ聖杯戦争の真実を教えてやろう
Gilgamesh...
Let me tell you the truth behind the Holy Grail War.
何だと
What?
The ritual here, in Fuyuki, is an attempt to open a passage to
the Root through the sacrifice of the souls of seven Heroic Spirits.
そもそもこの冬木の儀式はな
七体の英霊の魂を束ねて生贄とすることで
「根源」へと至る穴を空けようとする試みだ
七人のサーヴァントをすべて殺し尽くすことで「大聖杯」を起動させる
One can activate the Great Grail by killing all seven Servants.
七人全てだ
Yes, all seven.
分かるな
You understand?
That's why my master tried so hard to avoid using his Command Spells.
我が師があれほど令呪の消費を渋っていた理由がそれだ
He needs them to force his own Servant to
commit suicide once all the battles have ended.
すべての戦いが終わった後で
自らのサーヴァントを自決させるために必要だったからだ
時臣がオレに示した忠義は 全て嘘偽りだったと言うのか
So you're saying the loyalty Tokiomi has shown me was all a lie?
In the end, my master is simply a Mage to the core.
結局のところ 我が師は骨の髄まで「魔術師」だったというだけのことだ
英霊は崇拝しても その偶像には幻想など抱かない
He may worship a Heroic Spirit, but
he harbors no illusions about his idols.
Tokiomi...
時臣め 最後にようやく見所を示したな
You have finally proven your worth.
At last, that boring little man will be able to entertain me.
あの退屈な男も これでやっとオレを愉しませることができそうだ
What will you do now, King of Heroes?
さて どうする 英雄王
それでもなお お前は我が師に忠義立てして
Are you still going to remain loyal to
my master and punish me for rebelling?
この私の叛意を咎めるか
I don't know about that.
さあ どうしたものかな
Disloyal he may be, but Tokiomi still supplies me with mana.
いかに不忠者とはいえ 時臣は今なおオレに魔力を貢いでいる
Abandoning my Master would hinder my ability to remain materialized.
完全にマスターを見限ったのでは現界に支障をきたすしな
ああ そういえば一人
Oh, that reminds me.
令呪を得たものの相方がおらず
There happens to be a Master with Command Spells but
no partner, searching for a Servant unbound by contract.
契約から逸れたサーヴァントを求めているマスターがいたはずだった
そういえば そうだった
You're right, now that you mention it.
だが果たして その男
But is that man a worthy Master
in the eyes of the King of Heroes?
マスターとして英雄王の眼鏡に適うのかどうか
He will suffice.
問題あるまい
堅物すぎるのが玉に瑕だが 前途はそれなりに有望だ
He's slightly flawed in that he's rather stiff, but he has great potential for growth.
ゆくゆくは存分にオレを愉しませてくれるかもしれん
He may prove to be a fine source
of entertainment for me someday.
待っていたよ 綺礼
I've been waiting, Kirei.
I came to have a word before leaving Fuyuki.
冬木を退去する前に 一言ご挨拶に上がりました
私は君という弟子を得たことを今でも誇りに思っている
I'm still proud to have had you as my student.
どうか今後とも 亡きお父上のように君もまた
I hope you will maintain good relations with the Tohsakas, as your late father did in life.
遠坂との縁故を保っていってほしいと思うのだが
どうだろう
What do you say?
I could ask for nothing more.
願ってもないお言葉です
Once this Grail War is over, I'd like you to
help me train Rin as her senior apprentice.
今回の聖杯戦争が終わった後も
綺礼 君には兄弟子として凛の指導に当たって欲しいのだ
まあ簡略ではあるが 遺言状のようなものだ
It's a simple one, but this is a will of sorts.
万が一ということも考えておくべきだと思ってね
I thought it wise to prepare for the worst.
It leaves the Tohsaka family headship to Rin and
names you as her guardian until she comes of age.
凛に遠坂の家督を譲る旨の署名と
成人するまでの後見人として君を指名しておいた
お任せを
Leave it to me.
御息女については責任を持って見届けさせていただきます
I will do all I can to look after your daughter.
ありがとう
Thank you, Kirei.
綺礼
What is this?
これは
It's my gift to you.
君個人に対して私からの贈り物だ
Open it.
開けてみたまえ
アゾット剣だ
It's an Azoth dagger.
It symbolizes your mastery of the Tohsaka family magics and marks the end of your apprenticeship.
君が遠坂の魔道を修め 見習いの過程を終えたことを証明する品だ
You are far too kind to me.
至らぬこの身に 重ね重ねのご厚情
I cannot even begin to express my gratitude, my master.
感謝の言葉もありません 我が師よ
It is me who must thank you, Kotomine Kirei.
君にこそ感謝だ 言峰綺礼
これで私は 最後の戦いに臨むことができる
I can now prepare for the final battle.
もうこんな時間か
Look at the time.
I'm sorry to have kept you.
長く引き留めてしまって済まないね
飛行機の時間に間に合うといいのだが
I hope you will make it in time for your flight.
いいえ 心配無用です 我が師よ
No.
You need not worry, my master.
もとより飛行機の予約などしておりませんので
I never bought the ticket.
師よ あなたも我が父と同じ
Master...
You're just like my father.
最後の最後まで
You never understood me, even until the very end.
私という人間を理解できなかったのですよ
フン 興醒めな幕切れだ
Such a boring ending.
見よ この真抜けた死に顔を
Look at how stupid his dying face looks.
He did have a Servant in spirit form at hand.
すぐ傍に霊体化したサーヴァントを侍らせていたのだ
I don't blame him for lowering his guard.
油断したのも無理はあるまい
So you've already learned to jest.
早くも諧謔を身につけたか
That progress is worth praising.
その進歩ぶりは褒めておこう
どうだ 綺礼
Well, Kirei?
Do you feel slightly better about missing out on the chance to kill your father?
父親を殺められなかった悔しさが少しは晴れたか
本当に異存はないのだな 英雄王ギルガメッシュ
Do you really have no qualms
about this, Gilgamesh, King of Heroes?
お前がオレを飽きさせぬ限りにおいてはな
As long as you continue to amuse me.
さもなくば綺礼
Otherwise, Kirei...
覚悟を問われるべきは むしろお前だぞ
You're the one who should be questioning his own resolve.
汝の身は我の下に 我が命運は汝の剣に
Thou shalt come under my command,
and my fate shall be thy sword.
聖杯のよるべに従い
Abiding by the summons of the Holy Grail,
この意 この理に従うのなら
if thou dost accede to this will and reason...
誓おう 汝の供物を我が血肉と成す
I hereby swear.
Thy offering shall be my flesh, Kotomine Kirei...
言峰綺礼 新たなるマスターよ
My new Master.
さあ綺礼 始めるとしようか
Now, Kirei.
Let us begin.
お前の采配で見事 この喜劇に幕を引くがいい
Put an end to this farce however you see fit.
I shall reward you with the Grail.
褒美に聖杯を賜そう
Consider it done, King of Heroes.
異存はない
英雄王 お前もせいぜい愉しむことだ
May you have your fill of amusement.
Until the moment I find the answer I seek,
望む答えを得るその時まで
I shall gladly play the fool.
この身は道化に甘んじるとも
Episode 17
The Eighth Contract
Doushite sora wa konnani aokute
どうして空はこんなに青くて
Why is the sky so blue?
Nanimo kanashimi wo shiranu you ni
何も悲しみを知らぬように
As if oblivious to sadness
Itsumo tamerawazu ashita e to kuzureochiru
いつも躊躇わず明日へと崩れ落ちる
It crumbles incessantly to make way for a new day
Inochi wa tarinai mama umarete kuru no ne
命は足りないまま生まれてくるのね
I suppose we are born with our lives short
Kakeochita kokoro ni anata ga furete
かけおちた心にあなたが触れて
You have touched my torn heart
Futari de yuku mirai wa kegare no nai tsuyosa de
二人で行く未来は穢れのない強さで
Our future ahead is filled with a pure, unblemished strength
Sora wa takaku kaze wa utau
空は高く 風は歌う
The sky is vast, the wind is melody
Yume wo miteta yorokobi e to
夢を見てた喜びへと
Men will one day come to realize
Hito wa itsuka tadoritsukeru
人はいつか辿り着ける
The joy of chasing after a dream
Kodomo no hitomi de anata wa shinjita
子供の瞳であなたは信じた
With the eyes of a child, you've always had faith
Soba ni iru yo
そばにいるよ
I'll be right beside you
Kooritsuita mori wo nukete
凍りついた森を抜けて
As we pass through the frozen forest
Sono hitomi ga sekai no nageki ni mayowanu you ni
その瞳が世界の嘆きに迷わぬように
So that the world's sorrow will not taint your eyes
ケリィはさ どんな大人になりたいの
Kerry, what do you want to be when you grow up?
あの屋敷に行くのはやめなさい
Don't go to that mansion.
何だこれ
What is this?
後のことは自分で考えな
You decide the rest on your own.
お前にはまだ早過ぎる
It's still too early for you.
Someday, you'll have the power to change the world.
いつか君が手に入れるのは世界を変える力だよ
Next Episode
Distant Memories